Alan Wagner

Email: alanwagner101@gmail.com | Phone: 701-212-9576 | Minneapolis, MN 55411

GitHub: https://github.com/alanwagner101

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/alan-wagner-bb7942139

Portfolio: https://alanwagner101.github.io/New-Portfolio/

Multidisciplinary Full Stack Web Developer with a passion for problem solving and adapting to new and challenging tasks. Adept at working independently as well as collaborating with others to create intuitive and well thought out user experiences as well as clean and easy to read code for future developers. Bring leadership and communication experience from a decade's worth of relentless attentiveness and work ethic. Prepared to exceed expectation and create a real and lasting influence on my future employer.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, React, Node.JS, Express.JS, Handlebars, JSON.

Databases: MongoDB, Mongoose.js, MySQL, Sequelize.js, Google Firebase

Others: Git, Bash, Bootstrap, NPM, Heroku, Microsoft Office

APPLICATIONS BUILT

Gamers United

- This app allows gamers of all forms to host their own gaming events/tournaments in their area. Just say what game you want to play, when and where, and users can register to attend. It also has a news section to keep tabs on upcoming esports events as well as upcoming games.
- React, JSX, MongoDB, JavaScript, Bootstrap, CSS, Express.JS, NodeJS, HTML
- https://github.com/pwneill/redeem-team/graphs/contributors
- https://powerful-beyond-98279.herokuapp.com/

Pic Cycler

- Application built to allow users to add their favorite pictures to a live stream of pictures and lets them chat about each picture as they shuffle by.
- MySQL, Sequelize.JS, jQuery, Express.JS, HTML, CSS, Handlebars
- https://github.com/alanwagner101/PicCycler
- http://hidden-castle-32333.herokuapp.com/

Rock Paper Scissors

- Multiplayer online rock, paper, scissors game allowing two players to play and chat.
- Detects when a player joins or leaves.
- HTML, Bootstrap, jQuery, and Google Firebase
- https://github.com/alanwagner101/RPS-Multiplayer
- https://alanwagner101.github.io/RPS-Multiplayer

- National Park Service application that allows the user to search for parks and campsites and what to expect upon arrival.
- Uses the NPS, NASA, and Weather channel API to retrieve relative information.
- HTML, Bootstrap, jQuery, API, JSON
- https://github.com/alanwagner101/NaPSApp
- https://alanwagner101.github.io/Project1/

GIPHY App

- Application that allows the user to search for groups of gifs based off of user inputted key words.
- Save your favorite searches in buttons for later use.
- HTML, Bootstrap, ¡Ouery, API, JSON
- https://github.com/alanwagner101/GIPHYapp
- https://alanwagner101.github.io/GIPHYapp/

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Royal Foundry Craft Spirits

Bartender, Minneapolis, MN,

2018 - Present

Designing and building craft cocktails with our in house distilled spirits and hand-made simple syrups, shrubs, liqueurs, and bitters. I help with a lot of the prep work that goes into creating the spirits and other ingredients.

• Experience being creative with the tools i have been provided to create beautiful/great tasting cocktails from scratch.

The Window Store Home Improvements

Canvass Team Lead/Marketing Coordinator, St Anthony, MN

<u> 2015 - Present</u>

In charge of designing and implementing marketing promotions as well as training and coaching the canvass department employees.

- 3+ years of Sales/Customer Service experience.
- 3+ years of leadership of a group of 10 or more individuals.
- Promoted in the first 3 months from a canvasser position.

Bluestem Brands (Fingerhut)

Trainer, Quality Assurance/Team Lead, Specialty line rep, and CSR, St Paul, MN 2014 - 20

Helped build up the at home agent program in the Minneapolis/St. Paul area. Trained multiple groups to use our point of sale program, customer service database, and a number of other customer service resources.

- Learned IT troubleshooting for company owned programs.
- 3 years of leadership of over 5 different groups of trainees as well as several groups as a team lead.
- Was the first trainer in the company to train on the new point of sale program Evolve.

Tech Mahindra (Fingerhut)

Trainer, Quality Assurance/ Team Lead, and CSR, Fargo, ND

2012 - 2014

Started a test pilot for Bluestem Brands in an effort to bring more of the sales and customer service reps back onshore. I was in charge of training in all new hires as well as managing a team of representatives.

- Learned IT troubleshooting for company owned programs.
- 3 years of leadership of over 5 different groups of trainees as well as several groups as a team lead.
- Was the first trainer in the company to train on the new point of sale program Evolve.

Drunken Noodle/ Wasabi

Ran up the ranks quickly here starting as a dishwasher, then moving up to front of house (FOH) and so on until I had worked every position where-in I was promoted to manager with the responsibility of opening, closing, counting cash registers, making the employee schedule, and keeping track of and ordering stock.

• 3 years of leadership with a group of about 12 individuals under my care.

SELECTED CONTRIBUTIONS

- Attained a manager position within 1 year of starting, I was hired as a dishwasher (Drunken Noodle/ Wasabi).
- Oversaw a 2-year test pilot for an onshore sales team for Bluestem Brands company Fingerhut (Tech Mahindra).
- Orchestrated the push to bring more customer service jobs onshore by training at multiple classes of at home customer service reps (Bluestem Brands).
- Exceeded the owner's expectations as a canvasser and getting promoted to a team lead as well as marketing coordinator overseeing seasonal promotional offers (The Window Store).

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota,

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp, St. Paul, MN

Sep 2018 - Mar 2019

An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned consisted of HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars JS, & React Js.